[
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s most populous island?",
        "answer": "Java, Indonesia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Dacia?",
        "answer": "Romania"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Ceylon?",
        "answer": "Sri Lanka"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Dutch Guiana?",
        "answer": "Suriname"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Formosa?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Asia Minor?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state-chartered university is located in a town called Chapel Hill?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only National Park located in Michigan?",
        "answer": "Isle Royale National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "In land area, what is the largest country in South America?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What South American country is home to Atacama Desert?",
        "answer": "Chile"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Guyana?",
        "answer": "Georgetown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is the Dutch parliament in?",
        "answer": "The Hague"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city has the world`s largest castle complex?",
        "answer": "Prague, Czech Republic"
    },
    {
        "question": "What African landmark has a local name that means The Smoke that Thunders?",
        "answer": "Victoria Falls -- The Kololo tribe that was living in the area in the 1800s called it `Mosi-oa-Tunya,` or The Smoke that Thunders."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the modern name for Van Diemen`s Land?",
        "answer": "Tasmania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country`s national drink is sugarcane juice?",
        "answer": "Pakistan"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what modern day country did the seven Churches of Asia once exist?",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "question": "True champagne can only come from grapes grown in the Champagne region of what country?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Including all territories, where is the first place to see the sunrise each day in the U.S.?",
        "answer": "Peacock Point, Wake Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the most UNESCO World Heritage Sites?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you visit Reflection Canyon?",
        "answer": "Utah"
    },
    {
        "question": "How often does Old Faithful erupt?",
        "answer": "Approximately every 90 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is `The Windy City`?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "question": "What African country in which the entire population speaks the same language?",
        "answer": "Somalia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inverness is the capital of which region in the U.K.?",
        "answer": "Scottish Highlands -- It is a northeast coastal town near the famous Loch Ness. Edinburgh, is the capital of the lowlands."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Wales` largest city?",
        "answer": "Cardiff -- It is the capital of Wales and has a population of about 400,000."
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is part of the U.K., but not Great Britain?",
        "answer": "Northern Ireland -- Great Britain refers to the connected island of Britain, which is comprised of Scotland, England, and Wales."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the northernmost national park in the world?",
        "answer": "Northeast Greenland National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country did Barbados gain its independence from?",
        "answer": "United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city in Ohio is known as the `rubber capital of the US`?",
        "answer": "Akron"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the largest Great Lake?",
        "answer": "Lake Superior"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Magnolia State`?",
        "answer": "Mississippi"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city of Santa Cruz is located on the shores of what bay?",
        "answer": "Monterey Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Lake Havasu City?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sea, that is part of the Southern Ocean, has the alternative name `George IV Sea`?",
        "answer": "Weddell Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "An 1849 painting by Asher Durand, and a sculpture situated in Bailick Park in Midleton, Ireland,share what name?",
        "answer": "Kindred Spirits"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest North American country by land area?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major American city is nicknamed, `The Mile-High City?`",
        "answer": "Denver, Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is known as the `Mother of Presidents and the Mother of Statesmen`?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state was nicknamed `Old Dominion`?",
        "answer": "Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where were the 1960 Summer Olympics held?",
        "answer": "Rome, Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which famous city bridge is known locally as `The Coathanger`?",
        "answer": "Sydney Harbour Bridge"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Northern Mariana Islands?",
        "answer": "Saipan"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which of North America`s Great Lakes does the city of Buffalo stand?",
        "answer": "Lake Erie"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which European country is the resort town of Spa?",
        "answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mountain is also known as Monte Cervino and Mont Corvin?",
        "answer": "The Matterhorn"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which South American country to the Galapagos Islands belong?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which county of Ireland would you find the Twelve Bens mountain range?",
        "answer": "Galway"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the world`s largest protected nature reserve?",
        "answer": "Greenland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Zagreb is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Croatia"
    }
]